intellitxt.com 2013-05-30

# Vibrant Media — The Global Leader of In–Content Contextual Technology

Vibrant Media, Inc. (“ **Vibrant Media** ” “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) is a publisher-side technology company. We help our clients serve more relevant advertisements on their websites. We provide this privacy policy so we may inform you about how our technology (" **Technology** ") processes information for online advertisers, website owners, and other businesses that use our services (our " **Clients** "). This policy also outlines our privacy practices on our corporate Website (" **Website** "), [www.vibrantmedia.com](http://www.vibrantmedia.com/ "Vibrant Media"). If you have any questions regarding our privacy practices, please feel free to contact us by [clicking here](http://www.vibrantmedia.com/about/contact.asp?ref=privacy "Contact Vibrant"). By using the Website, you accept the policies and restrictions set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

**Topics:**

  1. Collection and Use of Information on this Website
  2. Collection and Use of Information through Our Technology
  3. Types of Information We Collect through Our Technology
  4. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties
  5. Controlling the Use of Your Information
  6. Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising
  7. Information Security
  8. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  9. Who can I ask if I have additional questions?

### 1\. Collection and Use of Information on this Website

_Personally Identifiable Information._ This Website is directed to our Clients and prospective Clients, who are businesses. The Website is not directed to consumers. We may collect Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) via this Website when a visitor voluntarily provides it to us. PII means name, postal address, email address and telephone number. We may use that information to respond to your requests and inquiries and for other purposes. The following are some specific use cases:

  * _Vibrant Media’s Inquiry Form_ \- The Vibrant Media Website contains an “inquiry form” for Clients and prospective Clients to request additional information about Vibrant Media’s products and services. The inquiry form requires web publishers to provide contact information (such as name and email address). Vibrant Media uses this information to contact such Clients and prospective Clients about the services on the Website in which they have expressed interest, and to help us provide excellent customer service to our Clients.
  * _Business Client Registration_ – As part of the business Client registration process, business Clients may be required to provide some PII. We may use this information to contact the business Client if there is a billing or order processing issue, to help us process invoices, and to otherwise provide our services to our business Client.
  * _Testimonials_ \- Some of our Clients agree to allow us to use their name and comments on the Website as part of testimonials. If you’ve agreed to have your name appear in a testimonial on this Website, you should be aware that your name and comment as well as other information displayed can be read, collected, or used by other users of this Website.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information._ We may collect Non-PII from visitors to this Website. Non-PII includes your IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, Internet browsing and usage habits, Internet Service Provider, domain name, the time/date of your visit to this Website, the referring URL and your computer's operating system.

_Cookies_ We use cookies on this Website. Cookies are small text files placed in a visitor’s browser. Cookies make using our Website easier for our Clients by, among other things, saving their login preferences. These cookies are restricted for use only on our Website, and do not transfer any PII to any other party. Through your browser settings, you may disable cookies. If you choose to disable your cookies setting or refuse to accept a cookie, some parts of the Website may not function properly or may be considerably slower. For more information about cookies please visit the Vibrant Media Cookie Policy by clicking here. 

_Third Party Websites_ The Website may contain links to and advertisements for websites operated by third parties whose privacy practices may differ from ours. Vibrant Media is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other websites. We encourage you to check the privacy policies of all websites that you visit.

_Updating / Deleting your PII_ If you'd like us to update, correct, or delete any PII that you have provided to us on this Website, please send your request to us by clicking here and we will process your request.

Back to Top

### 2\. Collection and Use of Information through Our Technology

_Overview of the Technology._ Our Clients may use our Technology to deliver advertisements that are intended to align with your current interests. This form of advertising, called "Interest Matching", delivers advertisements that are more relevant, interesting, and useful for you. Our Clients may also use our Technology for other purposes including to help measure the effectiveness of a campaign or to optimize other campaigns. 

Our Technology is designed to facilitate the delivery of contextual advertisements by highlighting certain words or phrases on our Client’s websites. It works like this: when a user scrolls over those words or phrases, our Technology then displays ads that are relevant to the highlighted text. We may use our Technology to identify your interests by the words that you have recently seen and read while online and by the websites visited, along with the advertisements that you have viewed and clicked on. We may use this information collected by our Technology to help make the online advertisements you see more relevant to you, for ad delivery and reporting, and other purposes. There is no PII transmitted or used in this process. You may encounter our Technology when you visit a web site: (1) where one of our Clients has enabled our text-based advertising solution; (2) where Vibrant Media, or one of our Clients, purchases online advertisements; and/or (3) where one of our Clients places a web beacon.

We may use non-PII and information provided by other entities to help make our client's advertising more relevant. Some of these entities participate in self-regulatory programs including the Digital Advertising Alliance's ("DAA") program. To learn about the DAA program as well as exercise choice with respect to those entities participating in the DAA program, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/ "About Ads").

Back to Top

### 3\. Types of Information We Collect through Our Technology

_Personally Identifiable Information._ We don't collect PII via our Technology.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information._ We may collect Non-PII via our Technology using cookies for many purposes including to help make the online advertisements you see more relevant to you, measure the effectiveness of a campaign, optimize a campaign, or for operational purposes. The cookie is used to collect Non-PII, including but not limited to, an anonymous and randomly assigned identification number, your IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, the referring URL, interactions with an ad, Internet Service Provider, and your computer’s operating system. We may also collect and maintain via cookies other Non-PII to create a data set of keyword interactions, also to assist us in showing you more relevant advertisements and help manage our advertising campaigns. This data set may include a list of search terms that you use to arrive on our Client’s website, keywords recently viewed by you, the time and date you clicked on or viewed one of our Client’s advertisements, and the web pages you viewed after you clicked on or viewed one of our Client’s advertisements. You may “opt out” of certain practices as explained below.

_Storage of Non-Personally Identifiable Information._ We retain the Non-PII collected via our Technology for up to 13 months. After 13 months, we remove the cookie identification numbers and IP addresses and store it for up to 5 years. We store this information for 5 years as required for financial records for our Clients. 

For more information about how we use cookies, please visit our Cookie Policy [www.vibrantmedia.com/cookies.asp](http://www.vibrantmedia.com/cookies.asp "Cookies Policy").

Back to Top

### 4\. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties 

_General._ We may at our discretion disclose PII and Non-PII (“ **Information** ”) to third parties when we believe we are obligated to do so by law, and to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to, fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person. We also may disclose Information when necessary to comply with a court order, legal process or other legal proceeding. Finally, we may transfer Information to a successor entity in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, sale of assets, bankruptcy, or other corporate change.

_PII._ Finally, we may transfer Information to a successor entity in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, sale of assets, bankruptcy, or other corporate change. PII. We may share PII with trusted third-party contractors who provide services for us. These third party contractors are limited in using the information we provide for purposes other than performing services at our direction. 

_Non-PII._ We may share aggregate Non-PII collected by us with third parties. For example, we may disclose to our Clients that 'blue banner ads' receive more clicks than 'orange banner ads;'.

Back to Top

### 5\. Controlling the Use of Your Information and Opting-Out

_Opting out from Interest Matching._ If you'd like to opt-out from having Vibrant Media collect and use Non-PII from your browser in connection with our Technology for Interest Matching advertising, please[ click here](http://intellitxt.com/opt_out/ch_optout.asp "Opting Out from Interest Matching"). When you opt out, we will place an opt-out cookie on your browser. The opt-out cookie tells us not to collect your Non-PII to tailor our online advertisement campaigns. However, we may continue to collect certain data for basic ad serving and other purposes such as counting the number of times a keyword has been clicked. Please note that if you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. 

Back to Top

### 6\. Participation in Self-Regulatory Programs

We support the cross industry, Self-Regulatory Principles as managed by the DAA (“ **DAA** ”) (for more information [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/ "About Ads")) To provide consumers with enhanced transparency, we display the DAA’s Ad Choices Icon in advertisements delivered across our network to help consumers understand how data is being used and to provide choices for consumers who want more control. Vibrant Media also is a member of (1) the Internet Advertising Bureau (“IAB”) and abides by IAB’s Member Code of Conduct, which you can review by [clicking here](http://www.iab.net/public_policy/codeofconduct "IAB’s Member Code of Conduc") and (2) is a participating network with the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NA** I”) opt-out tool for behavior advertising, which you can review at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "NAI Opt-out tool"). 

Our Clients may separately collect Non-PII or other information from you when you visit their websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the privacy practices of our Clients, and we are not responsible for their collection of Non-PII or other information from you. 

Back to Top

### 7\. Information Security

The security of your information is important to us, including but not limited to the PII collected via the Website. We have implemented security measures to protect the information in our care, both during transmission and once we receive it. This includes, but is not limited to the use of firewalls and encryption. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Back to Top

### 8\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may modify this privacy policy from time to time. Please return here frequently to review this privacy policy.

Back to Top

###  9\. Who can I ask if I have additional questions?

If you have any questions or comments about [www.vibrantmedia.com](http://www.vibrantmedia.com/ "Vibrant Media") or about this privacy statement, please contact:

**Via mail:** Vibrant Media, Inc. 565 Fifth Avenue, 16th Floor, New York, NY 10017   
**Via email:** [info@vibrantmedia.com](mailto:info@vibrantmedia.com "Contact Vibrant")   
**Via telephone:** (646) 312-6100

Last updated March 12, 2013

Back to Top
